It's starting!
[Note: Written on Elizabeth's sign. Parody of an MGM silent film.]
Elizabeth's first errand
Starring
Elizabeth
Kotaro Katsura
All the people in Edo
Katsura: Elizabeth, I need you to run an errand.
An errand?
Katsura: There's a sale on shampoo at the Oedo Mart.
Why me?
Katsura: I'm a wanted member of the Anti-Foreigner Faction, though I may not look the part.
Katsura: I can't go shopping at a supermarket in broad daylight...
You can keep the change.
Hostess Bar
Only 2000 yen!!
Hostess Bar Old Lady Paradise
Nakamura Restaurant
Flower Shop
Hemorrhoids. Your Worries
Katsura: Elizabeth isn't back yet...
Where's the Oedo Store again?
Where is the Oedo Store?
Michael: I can't read Japanese.
I'm trying to get to the Oedo Store.
Old Man: My eyes aren't too good.
Where is the Oedo Store located??
Pedro: How about you listen to my story instead?
すみません
大江戸ｽﾄｱって どこですか？
Pedro: This weird kid showed up at my place again last night.
Pedro: They ring my doorbell and say...
20 minutes later
Pedro: So yeah, this story doesn't really have a punch line or anything.
Where is the Oedo Store located?
Pedro: Huh? Oedo Store?
Pedro: Never heard of it.
Kagura: Elizabeth, what's up?
Big Sale
...My spare sign...
is gone.
What do I do?
What do I do?!
Excuse me.
[Note: Voice by supervisor, Shinji Takamatsu.]
Where's the Oedo Store?
Kagura: Over there.
Katsura: Oh!! What a relief, Elizabeth.
Katsura: This is...
conditioner.
Katsura: Unbelievable!! This is unbelievable!!
Katsura: I expected you to be a little more useful.
Katsura: What are you going to do if my long hair becomes all dry?!
Katsura: I don't want to end up with dandruff. I'll have a hard time leading my men if my head's covered with flakes.
Katsura: Everyone will be staring at the dandruff instead of listening to what I say. Ahh, I expected you to be a little more useful. A preschooler could run this errand for me. I saw it on TV the other day, and I almost cried. But no, look at you.
Whoohoo!
[It was back in winter...]
["It Takes a Bit of Courage to Enter a Street Vendor's Stand"]
♪♪～
[The Whinery]
Welcome!
(親父)へい！ らっしゃい！
(ちんざむ)いや～｡
Man, it's freezing today, old man.
今日は冷え込むな～ ｵﾔｼﾞ｡
ほんとにねぇ！
It sure is.
It might snow soon.
近いうちに
雪でも降るんじゃないかねえ｡
They keep talking about global warming,
温暖化だなんて
いわれてますがね｡
but Earth's only getting warmer on the outside.
あったまってんのは
地球の表面ばかりでさぁ｡
Here in Edo, the town and the people's hearts are just getting chillier.
江戸は 町も人の心も
冷えゆく一方ですよ｡
Got that right.
(ちんざむ)まったくだよ｡
ｵﾚのふところも➡
When will I get some warm action going on?
[Note: "Warm action" refers to getting some more money in his wallet.]
いつになったら
温暖化するんだか｡
ﾍﾍﾍ 旦那！ せいぜいこいつで
温暖化してくだせえや！
Warm yourself up with some of this, big guy.
(ちんざむ)でも 悪いんだけど➡
Sorry, but I'm looking for something sweeter.
もうちょっと甘いもんが
飲みてえんだよ ｵﾚ｡
Sweeter?
(親父)甘いもの？
(ちんざむ)悪いんだけど それ➡
Sorry, but could you mix a little coffee milk or strawberry milk in there?
ｺｰﾋｰ牛乳か いちご牛乳で
割ってくれる？
Can you fix one up?
できる？ そういうの？
いや～ 全然できますけど｡
Absolutely, but you have unique tastes, big guy.
ずいぶん変わった
飲み方しますねぇ 旦那も｡
(ちんざむ)
あれだよ 疲れたときは➡
You know what they say.
Something sweet helps when you're exhausted.
甘いもん とりたくなるって
いうだろ？
That's right, big guy. You look awfully tired.
(親父)そういや 旦那｡
えらく気だるそうな顔してますよ｡
頭も白髪だらけだし｡
And your hair's all white.
Did something happen?
なんか あったんですか？
(ちんざむ)それは 生まれつきだ！
I was born this way.
(親父)なんか悩みごとでも
あるんなら➡
If you've got something on your mind, why not let it out here?
ここで ｸﾞﾁこぼしていったら
どうですか？
Huh?
(ちんざむ)は？
Men are vain creatures.
(親父)男は 見栄張って
なんぼの生き物だ｡
They never complain, whether at work or at home.
職場でも家庭でも
ｸﾞﾁは こぼせねえ｡
Some things can only be told to a stranger.
赤の他人だからこそ
話せることもあんでしょ？
Men need a place like this.
必要なんですよ
男には こういう場所が｡
(ちんざむ)別に悩みなんて
ねえけど…｡
There really isn't anything on my mind...
Besides, the audience is watching.
だいたい
視聴者の目があるからね｡
大丈夫です｡
ｳﾁは お客さんのﾌﾟﾗｲﾊﾞｼｰは➡
Don't worry. This place protects the privacy of its customers.
完璧に守られてるんで｡
これ一切 顔見えない感じなんで｡
Like how they can't even see your face.
Ah, I see.
ああ そうなの！
ええ｡
Yeah.
今回は 全編こういう感じなんで
誰だか全然わかりませんよ｡
It'll be like this the entire episode, so nobody will know who you are.
なんでも しゃべれます｡
ああ そうなんだ！
Feel free to say anything.
Ah, I see.
ちなみに ここじゃ
顔見知りと出会っても➡
By the way, the practice here
is to pretend you don't recognize each other if you're acquaintances.
知らねえ顔してやるのが
ﾂｳの飲み方なんです｡
ひとつ…
好きなだけｸﾞﾁって下さい｡
First: Complain all you want.
Second: Come alone.
ふたつ…
一人で来て下さい｡
Third: Pretend you don't recognize each other if you're acquaintances.
みっつ… 知り合いに会っても
知らぬﾌﾘをして下さい｡
Fourth: Forget everything you hear in this place and do not tell a soul.
よっつ… ここで聞いた事は
他言しないでｽｸﾞに忘れて下さい｡
A place where you can feel free to complain.
なんの しがらみにもとらわれず
ｸﾞﾁを吐ける場｡
That's what this stall is for.
それが ｳﾁの店なんですよ｡
ほら 旦那も
今日は 余計なこと考えずに➡
Come on, big guy. Don't think too much and just spill your guts today.
腹ん中 ぜ～んぶ
ぶちまけてってくだせぇ｡
Brush off all the dirt from this sad world so you can feel refreshed tomorrow, yeah?
浮世のｱｶを全部落として➡
明日から
ｽｯｷﾘ生きていきやしょうよ ねぇ！
Okay, coffee milk with shochu.
はい！ ｺｰﾋｰ牛乳酎｡
(ちんざむ)ｸﾞﾁねぇ｡
いつも ｸﾞﾁってるからなぁ ｵﾚ｡
Complain, you say?
Actually, I'm complaining all the time, so I don't really have anything...
そんなには たまってない…｡
(ﾏﾖ侍)ｳｰｯｽ｡
'Sup.
へい らっしゃい！
あぁ 旦那すまねぇな｡
Hey, welcome!
Ah, sorry, big guy.
ちょいと詰めてもらえやすか？
Could you slide over a bit?
Give this handsome samurai a seat.
この二枚目のお侍さんに
席空けてやって｡
(ﾏﾖ侍)あぁ すみません｡
Ah, sorry.
Not at all. Go ahead.
(ちんざむ)いえいえ
どうぞ どうぞ｡
Whew, I can finally warm myself up.
(ﾏﾖ侍)ふぅ～
ようやく温まれるわ｡
It's freezing out there.
(ちんざむ)冷えますね｡
今日は ﾎﾝﾄ急にきたよね｡
Came out of nowhere, really.
It wasn't this bad yesterday.
昨日までは
そんなでもなかったのに…｡
Indeed.
(ﾏﾖ侍)ﾎﾝﾄっすね｡
こりゃ今年は確実に雪が…｡
We're pretty much guaranteed to have snow...
Eh? Why did the two of you suddenly stop talking?
えっ？ どうしやした お二人さん｡
急に黙っちまって… まさか！
Don't tell me...
(ちんざむ)えっ いや… 別に｡
Ah, no. It's nothing.
(ﾏﾖ侍)うぅ… ｺﾞﾎﾝ！
あの ｵﾔｼﾞ 熱燗｡
Hey, pops.
Give me hot sake.
あと ﾁｸﾜとｶﾞﾝﾓとﾀﾏｺﾞ｡
へい｡
And a fish cake, a tofu fritter, and an egg.
[Note: Fish cakes and tofu fritters are popular items in an Oden hotpot.]
Gotcha.
あと… いつもの｡
And the usual...
へい ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでございやすよね｡
Gotcha. Mayonnaise, right?
(ちんざむ)あの…
結構 来るんですか？ この店｡
Uh, do you come here often?
Huh?
(ﾏﾖ侍)えっ？
(ちんざむ)いや… あの 今➡
Well, you just asked for the usual...
いつもの って…｡
Do you have a lot of complaining to do?
結構 あの ｸﾞﾁとか
たまってる感じで？
(ﾏﾖ侍)いやいや… ちょっとね｡
ほんの２～３回かな うん｡
Nah, only once in a while.
Only been here two or three times, yeah.
You've been here at least fifty times.
50回くらい来てますね｡
(ﾏﾖ侍)あっ ちょっとｵﾔｼﾞ！
余計なこと言わないで｡ やめて｡
Uh, pops?
Could you butt out? Please stop.
(ちんざむ)えっ!?
今日も ｸﾞﾁ言いに？
Huh? You're here today to complain again?
No, I'm just here for a drink today.
(ﾏﾖ侍)いえいえ
今日は 普通に飲みに…｡
Is it that gorilla boss of yours again?
また あのｺﾞﾘﾗ上司のことですか？
ｳﾎｯ ｳﾎｯ！
Pops, keep your mouth shut.
(ﾏﾖ侍)ｵﾔｼﾞ！ 余計なこと
言わないで！ やめて!!
Stop it!
(ちんざむ)へぇ～
上司 ｺﾞﾘﾗなんですか！
Huh, your boss is a gorilla?
大変ですね そりゃｸﾞﾁも出るわ｡
Sounds hard... No wonder you want to complain.
(ﾏﾖ侍)いやいや 違うんだよ｡
No, you've got it wrong.
Though he's a gorilla.
ｺﾞﾘﾗだけど… 別に悪口とか
ﾈﾁﾈﾁ言ってるんじゃなくて…｡
It's not like I'm badmouthing him all the time.
That's right. Instead of badmouthing him all the time, you just go...
そうですよね｡
ﾈﾁﾈﾁ悪口っていうか 毎回簡潔に➡
死ね！ って
言ってるだけですもんね｡
"Die!" usually.
(ﾏﾖ侍)ｵﾔｼﾞ！ 死ね！ お前が死ね！
Pops!
Die!
You die!
No, listen to me, big guy.
いや 聞いてくださいよ 旦那｡
こちらのﾏﾖ侍さんの上司｡
The mayo samurai's boss is always pestering this woman.
ある女性に
しつこく つきまとってて➡
で 毎回ね この方が その尻拭いを
してるってわけでさぁ｡
And this guy has to clean up afterwards every time.
I see. That sounds rough.
(ちんざむ) ああ そう 大変だね｡
Sounds rough, but "Die!" was a little shocking.
大変だけど ｢死ね｣は
ちょっと衝撃的だったね｡
No, when I say die...
(ﾏﾖ侍)い… いや 死ねっていうか
それは 言葉のあやっていうか➡
It's like a figure of speech...
Like an expression of love...
愛するがゆえの ｢死ね｣だよ｡
If I really wanted him to die, I wouldn't tell him to die.
本当に 死ねなんて思ってたら
死ねなんて言えないからね｡
ちょっと わかってるよね？
Hey, you understand, right?
ｵﾔｼﾞ ちょっともっかい
あの看板あげて もっかいあげて｡
Pops, raise the sign again. One more time.
You understand, right?
わかってるよね？
よく見て よく見て！
Look carefully. Look carefully at the fourth item!
４番目 よく見て
穴があくほど見て！
Stare long and hard!
I got it. I got it. I got it.
(ちんざむ)わかってる
わかってるもう｡ 大丈夫 大丈夫｡
Don't worry. Don't worry.
(ﾏﾖ侍)ﾎﾝﾄにわかったんだな？
You understand, right?
あ～ ちょっと旦那
３番目よく見て｡
Hold on, big guy.
Look carefully at the third item.
Hey, pops! I'm back!
(ｺﾞﾘ)おう ｵﾔｼﾞ
また来ちゃったよ ｱﾊﾊﾊｯ｡
Ah, Gori-san. It's been a long time.
やあ ｺﾞﾘさん 久しぶりですね！
困った人だ もう
できあがってるじゃねえですか｡
What a troublemaker.
You're drunk already, aren't you?
Well, it was freezing out there today.
(ｺﾞﾘ)いや～ 今日冷えるからさ｡
So I had a drink over there.
ちょっとそこで いっぱい
ひっかけてきちゃったよ！
But now is when I get serious!
でも こっからが本番だよ！
おっ 今日はまた
ぐちり屋がいっぱい揃ってるな｡
Oh, we've got ourselves a bunch of complainers here today!
This looks fun!
こりゃ楽しみだ！ ｶﾞﾊﾊﾊｯ｡
Ah?
ﾊｯ…｡
どうしたんですかい ｺﾞﾘさん｡
Eh? What's wrong, Gori-san, Mayo Samurai-san?
ﾏﾖ侍さん 顔色悪いですよ｡
You look pale.
ほらほら
何やってんですか 詰めて詰めて｡
Come on, what are you doing?
Slide over. Slide over.
ｺﾞﾘさん体でかいから
できるだけ詰めてやってね｡
Gori-san's got a big body, so make plenty of room.
いや～ 今ね ちょうど
盛り上がってたとこなんですよ｡
Well, we were just enjoying ourselves.
このﾏﾖ侍さんの話で｡
Listening to the mayo samurai's story.
(ﾏﾖ侍)いやいやいや ｵﾔｼﾞ
その話はもういいんじゃない？
No, no, pops.
Can't we drop that subject already?
Can't we drop it already?
それはもういいんじゃない？
(ｺﾞﾘ)えっ 何 何の話？
Huh? What? What story?
実はね この人の上司 ｺﾞﾘ…｡
Fact is, this guy's boss is a gori-
(ﾏﾖ侍)あ～っ！
あれもしかして UFOじゃね？
Ah! What?! Is that UFO?!
Uh, you realize that UFOs are flying around all the time in this world.
(ｺﾞﾘ)いや UFOって お前 もう
普通に飛んでるからね この世界｡
そのｺﾞﾘﾗが女性に
しつこくつきまとって➡
And that gorilla's always pestering this woman and he thinks the gorilla should just die-
大変なんで もう死に…｡
Look!
(ﾏﾖ侍)見て あれ絶対UFOだって！
That's definitely a UFO!
おい ちょっとみんなで
見に行ってみようぜ！
Hey, let's go check it out!
Heh...
(ｺﾞﾘ)へ へぇ～ 大変ですね
なんか ふ～ん ｺﾞﾘﾗ上司か｡
That kinda sounds rough...
Your boss is a gorilla, huh?
奇遇ですね｡ ｵﾚとあだ名
一緒なんですよ その人｡
What a coincidence.
I have the same nickname as that person.
あ～ そういやそうだね ｺﾞﾘさん｡
Ah, that's right, Gori-san.
あれ？ ｺﾞﾘさん なんか
涙目になってやせんか？
Huh?
Gori-san, are you crying?
(ｺﾞﾘ)えっ？ な なってないけど｡
I'm not!
全然なってないけど
ｺﾞﾐ入ったかな？ 花粉症かなこれ｡
Not at all! Just got something in my eye!
I have allergies!
Uh, can I leave now?
(ﾏﾖ侍)あの ｵﾚ
もうちょっと帰っていいかな｡
えっ？
(ﾏﾖ侍)ちょっと飲みすぎて➡
Eh?
I'm feeling sick after drinking too much.
具合悪くなってきた｡
ちょいと
待ってくださいよ ﾏﾖ侍さん｡
Hold on, Mayo Samurai-san.
ｺﾞﾘさんの話も
聞いてやってくだせえよ｡
Listen to what Gori-san has to say.
This gorilla's completely different from yours.
同じｺﾞﾘでも
こっちのｺﾞﾘは 全然違いますよ｡
No, no, no, no, no! It's okay!
(ｺﾞﾘ)いやいや… いやいいって！
ｵﾚの話はいいって ｵﾔｼﾞ！
They don't need to hear my story!
This gorilla's in a relationship with a hostess girl right now.
実はこのｺﾞﾘさん 今あるｷｬﾊﾞ嬢と
交際してるんですけどもねぇ｡
Ah, wait!
でね ｺﾞﾘさんは
いつもその女性を見守って➡
And this gorilla is always watching over her as a bodyguard.
ﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰｶﾞｰﾄﾞして
あげてるらしいんですよ｡
Wow... That's impressive.
(ちんざむ)はぁ～ すごいね｡
ﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰｶﾞｰﾄﾞしてるんだ｡
He's her bodyguard...
A bodyguard that hides under eaves and stuff...
軒下とか潜り込んで
ﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰｶﾞｰﾄﾞしてるんだ｡
いい男でしょ？
いまどきこんな男はいない｡
Great man, right?
You won't find anyone else like this these days.
You won't.
(ちんざむ)いないね
そんなﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰｶﾞｰﾄﾞいないね｡
You won't find a bodyguard like that.
That wouldn't be called a bodyguard.
そんなのﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｰｶﾞｰﾄﾞとはいわないね｡
でもって この女がね ｺﾞﾘさんが
そこまでしてるのにだよ➡
But even after everything Gori-san has done, this woman hasn't let him do...
いまだに一発も…｡
(ｺﾞﾘ)あ～っ！ あれもしかして➡
Ah! Isn't that Kazuo Umezu?!
[Note: Kazuo Umezu is considered the godfather of Japanese horror manga.]
梅図かずおじゃね？
どうせね➡
He's going as a customer, so you'd think she could show her appreciation by letting him...
店で体で客とってんだろうから➡
ｵﾚにも 一発くらいやらせて…｡
Look!
(ｺﾞﾘ)聞けよ！
あれ絶対 梅図かずおだって！
That has to be Kazuo Umezu!
Let's all go and do the famous hand sign!
[Note: "Guwashi!" is a handsign used in the manga "Makoto-chan" by Kazuo Umezu.]
おいちょっと
みんなで ｢ｸﾞﾜｼ｣やってこようぜ！
最低だと思いませんか この女｡
Don't you find this woman pathetic?
ｺﾞﾘさんと まったく
つり合わねえでしょ こんな女｡
She's a terrible match for Gori-san here.
ｵﾚはね さいさん
別れろって言ってんですけど｡
I keep telling him to break up with her,
なんせこの人 いい人だから｡
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)こんばんは｡
but he's such a nice guy.
Good evening.
(ｺﾞﾘ/ﾏﾖ侍)おっ！
あ～ いらっしゃい ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃん｡
Ah, welcome, Pony-chan.
[Note: Nicknamed that after her ponytail.]
あ あれ 今日店休み？
ええ｡
Er? Do you have the night off?
Yes, I was just stopping by on my way back from shopping.
ちょっと
買い物帰りに寄ったんですけど｡
Um, I made too many omelets,
あのこれ卵焼き作りすぎちゃって｡
いつもお世話になってる
ｵﾔｼﾞさんにと思って｡
so I thought I might offer my appreciation for imposing all the time.
あ あぁ… すまないね｡
Ah, ah...
Thanks as always, Pony-chan...
いつもありがとうよ ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃん｡
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)あの｡
あぁ 座って 座って！
Um...
Ah! Have a seat. Have a seat.
ほら 男子！ 席詰める｡
Come on, men!
Slide over!
待ちに待った
女子のご登場だ｡
We've finally got a woman here.
ひょっとして ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃん
さっきの話 聞こえてた？
Did you hear what we were talking about, Pony-chan?
いえ 何も｡
あぁ よかった｡
No, I didn't hear a thing.
Ah, isn't that great, Gori-san?
ｺﾞﾘさん
ﾁｬﾝｽ逃がさずに済んだよ｡
You didn't lose your chance.
どうだい
この娘にのりかえたら｡
Why not switch over to this lady?
She's a good girl.
ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃんは いい娘だよ｡
(ｺﾞﾘ)ぐへっ！
Huh?
あれ？ どうしやした 皆さん｡
What's wrong, everyone?
血の気がｾﾞﾛですよ｡
You're all pale as ghosts.
ｺﾞﾘさん あれ？
Gori-san...
Huh?
ｺﾞﾘさん なんか
口から泡出てますよ｡
Gori-san's foaming at the mouth.
まあ どうしたのかしら？
大丈夫ですか？
My, I wonder what's wrong.
Are you okay?
あれ？
何か背中から生えてますね｡
Huh? Something's growing out of his back?
Onion? It's a green onion.
ﾈｷﾞ… ﾈｷﾞだわ！
Green onion growing from his back...
背中からﾈｷﾞが…｡
Or no, more than growing, it's burrowing in!
いや 生えてるっていうか
刺さってるね｡
(ﾏﾖ侍)ｺﾞﾘさ～ん！
こりゃ てえへんだ！
Gori-san!
This is terrible!
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)通り魔だわ きっと
通り魔の仕業よ 怖いわね｡
It must be a phantom killer.
The work of a phantom killer.
How terrifying...
ﾈｷﾞで人を刺せる通り魔なんて
聞いたことねえよ！
I've never heard of a killer that stabs people with green onions!
(ちんざむ)
ｺｲﾂは 相当なﾊﾞｹﾓﾝの仕業だな｡
This must be the work of a real monster.
To harden a sprig of green onion to such a degree and stab without being noticed...
ﾈｷﾞを硬質化させて
気配もなく一突き｡
物質系能力者か｡
They must be an enhancer type of nen power.
[Note: A parody of HUNTER X HUNTER.]
いや こいつは 早いとこ
店じまいしたほうがよさそうだ｡
I should probably close up soon.
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)大丈夫ですよ
ﾀｰｹﾞｯﾄは始末したから➡
Don't worry.
The target's been eliminated, so the killer won't return to the scene of the crime.
もう犯行現場には
戻ってきませんよ｡
さあ 飲みましょう｡
Come, let's drink.
Pops, I'm taking Gori-san to the hospital!
(ﾏﾖ侍)ｵﾔｼﾞ ｵﾚ ちょっと
ｺﾞﾘさん 病院連れて行くから➡
ちょっと 行ってくるから！
(親父)すまないね ﾏﾖ侍さん｡
I'm off then!
Sorry about this, Mayo Samurai-san.
(ちんざむ)おい 待て！
ｵﾚを１人にするつもりか！
Hey! Wait!
You're going to leave me alone here?!
ｵﾚを 怒り狂うﾊﾞｹﾓﾝの檻に
１人残していくつもりか！
Leave me alone in a cage with an enraged monster?!
What are you talking about?
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)
何をしゃべっているんですか？
N-No, I was worried about Gori-san, so I was thinking about tagging along...
い いや… ｵﾚも
ちょっと ｺﾞﾘさん心配だから➡
ちょっと つき添おうかな なんて｡
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)いや でも
もう行っちゃいましたよ｡
But they're already gone.
That was fast!
早っ！ 一瞬であんな遠くまで
早っ！
All the way over there in no time!
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)もういいじゃないですか｡
Just forget about it.
Why not have a drink with me?
こちらに来て
一緒に飲みませんか？
Oh, Pony-chan?
あれれ？ なんだい ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃん｡
You prefer this guy over Gori-san?
ｺﾞﾘさんより こっちの旦那のほうが
お気に入りかい｡
ｳﾌ お酒お酌します｡
I'll pour the sake for you.
あぁ いいね
絵になるじゃねえかい｡
That's nice. Quite a pretty picture.
なかなかお似合いだよ
お二人さん｡
You two look great together.
ｱﾊﾊ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ そうですか｡
You think?
こちらの店には
よく来られてるんですか？
Do you come to this place often?
いや 今日が
初めてなんですけど➡
No, this is my first time here.
たまたま
ぶらり途中下車しただけで➡
I just happened to get off the train early and noticed this oddly named place: the Whinery...
[Note: Parody of TV show  "Burari Tochu Gesha (Getting off the train early)."]
すごい変わった店ですよね
ぐちり屋なんて｡
あの ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃ… ﾎﾟﾆｰ様は➡
Uh, does P-Pony-ch...
Does Pony-sama come here to complain often?
結構 ここに ｸﾞﾁりに来てる
感じなんですか？
It's been this long I'd say.
これくらいですかね｡
あっ ５回｡
Ah, five times.
That's more than what I was expecting...
思ったより
あれなんですね｡
５年くらい通い詰めてますわ｡
どんだけ!?
She's been coming here for five years.
Holy cow!
How much pent-up hate does she have?!
どんだけ 恨みつらみ
抱えてんの！
どんだけ
ｸﾞﾁこぼしに来てんの！
How much complaining has she done?!
The first time was when she came along with her late father long ago, who often came here to complain.
亡くなった親父さんが
よくここに ｸﾞﾁりに来てて➡
小さい頃 一緒についてきたのが
最初だったかね｡
生粋のｸﾞﾁり屋だよ
ｸﾞﾁりのｽﾍﾟｼｬﾘｽﾄだよ｡
A bona-fide whinery!
A whinery specialist!
She's been through a lot, though she may not look that way.
こう見えて 苦労人だからね｡
She lost her parents when she was young
幼くして 両親 亡くして➡
今まで たった１人で
弟さん守ってきたんだ｡
and she's watched over her little brother by herself this whole time.
問題は その弟さんだよね｡
That little brother is the problem.
Most of her complaining these days is about that little brother.
最近のｸﾞﾁは
目下その弟さんのｸﾞﾁだもんね｡
Ah, he must be an undependable little brother.
あぁ 頼りない
弟さんなんでしょうね｡
だいたい想像つきますよ｡
I can already picture it.
ﾒｶﾞﾈかけてて あれでしょ？
Glasses and that whole package.
いや 問題は弟さんじゃなくて➡
Oh, the problem isn't with her brother but with the people around him.
その周りにいるﾔﾂみてえでね｡
最近 弟さん 妙な連中に
入れ込んでるらしくって｡
Her brother seems to have joined a bad bunch of people.
ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃん 何だっけ？
Pony-chan, what was it about that permanently white-haired, always broke, and irresponsible...
あの白髪頭の万年金欠の
ちゃらんぽらん｡
ちんかす侍です｡
そう ちんざむだ｡
Smegma Samurai.
Ah, that's it.
Smeggy Sammy.
いや 略さなくても
いいんじゃないですか｡
Uh, is there really a need to abbreviate it?
ひどすぎるんじゃないですか
それは｡
Isn't that a little too cruel?
なんか そのちんざむのところで
働くようになってから➡
Her brother's gotten weird ever since he started working for Smeggy Sammy.
弟さん
おかしくなっちゃったみてえでね｡
なんか 部屋には ｶﾞﾁｶﾞﾁになった
ﾃｨｯｼｭが転がってるわ➡
Tissues all over the place in his room.
朝起きたら 勝手に
自分のﾊﾟﾝﾂ洗ってるわで➡
Washing his underwear by himself in the morning.
昔は そんな子じゃ
なかったらしいんでさあ｡
He didn't used to be that way.
(ちんざむ)それ ちんざむ
関係ないよね 全然｡
That's got nothing to do with Smeggy Sammy.
ただの自然の摂理だよね？
That's a part of nature.
Oh? Really?
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)えっ そうなんですか？
どういう摂理なんですか？
What kind of nature would this be?
(ちんざむ)い… いや
ちんざむも ちんざむで➡
Well, I'm sure that Smeggy Sammy is working hard in his own way.
それなりに
がんばってると思うよ ｵﾚは｡
The fact that the brother follows him when he has no money
金もねえのに そうやって
そばに置いてるってのは➡
それなりに 弟さんを
かわいがって…｡
shows how much he cares for the brother...
What could you possibly know about Smeggy Sammy?
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)あなたに
ちんざむの何がわかるんですか？
(ちんざむ)お前より
確実に知ってるわ!!
I know more than you do!
I understand Smeggy Sammy 100%!
100ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄ
ちんざむのこと 知ってるわ!!
Well, she keeps complaining about how she can't do anything about Smeggy Sammy these days.
まあ その ちんざむを
どうにかできねえかって➡
最近は そんなｸﾞﾁばっかりでね｡
まあ ｸﾞﾁっていうか
計画っていったほうがいいのかね｡
Well, it might be considered plotting instead of complaining.
(ちんざむ)何？ 計画って｡
What do you mean by plotting?
That sounds really scary...
なんか すご～い
怖い響きなんだけど｡
Well, he seems to be very skillful, so she has to create her own opening.
まあ 相当な手だれらしいんでね｡
よっぽど うまく隙を突かねえと｡
酒 たらふく飲ませて
泥酔させたり｡
Like letting him drink until he's completely smashed.
(ちんざむ)おい！ お前ら
いったい 何 企んでんだ!!
Hey!
What are you two plotting?!
ちんざむを いったい
どうするつもりだ!?
What are you going to do to Smeggy Sammy?!
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)あら さっき
買ったはずのﾈｷﾞが ないわ｡
Oh, the green onion I bought is gone.
Excuse me, I need to go buy another one.
すみません ちょっと
もう一回 買いにいってきます｡
(ちんざむ)
凶器 調達しにいったよ!?
She just went to procure a weapon!
やっぱ ｱｲﾂの仕業だったよ｡
It was her!
She's going to leave a green onion sticking out of Smeggy Sammy's back!
ちんざむの背中にも
ﾈｷﾞを生やさせるつもりか｡
ｵ… ｵﾔｼﾞ ｵﾚちょっと
急用 思い出したから帰るわ｡
O-Old man, I just remembered something I have to take care of.
お代 ここに置いとくぞ｡
I'll leave the money here.
Ah, hold on, big guy.
あっ ちょいと
待ってくだせえ 旦那｡
(ちんざむ)何だよ？
What?
I have something to tell you.
ひとつ 言っておきたいことが
ありやしてね｡
ｵﾚは 何十年も
人のｸﾞﾁを聞いてきた｡
I've been listening to people complain for decades.
何千何万のｸﾞﾁを
ずっと聞き続けてきた｡
I've heard thousands, tens of thousands of complaints.
人の悪口 仕事の不満｡
Badmouthing people, problems at work, stuff that gets you down.
気の滅入るようなもの
ばっかりでさぁ｡
だが そんなｸﾞﾁを なぜ 何十年も
聞き続けることができたのか｡
But I was able to bear it all for decades.
ｸﾞﾁの裏には
愛情があるからでさあ｡
That's because there's love behind every complaint.
Why won't things go my way when I'm working so hard at my job?
こんなに仕事を
一生懸命やってるのに➡
なぜ 思うとおりにならない｡
さっきの連中も
そうだったでしょう？
That's how it was with those other guys, right?
ｸﾞﾁってのは すべて➡
Complaints are just an expression of love when something doesn't go your way.
思うとおりにならない
愛情からくる ただのぼやき｡
ただのﾉﾛｹ話と
変わりゃしねえんですよ｡
Like a form of bragging.
ここまで言やあ
もう わかるでしょ？ 旦那｡
You should understand what I'm trying to say, big guy.
いや…｡
No, Smegma Samurai.
ちんかす侍｡ ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃんのこと
よろしくお願いしますね｡
Take good care of Pony-chan.
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)あら もう
店じまいしてしまったの？
Oh? He already closed.
あっ… ああ｡ 急用があるとかで｡
Y-Yeah, something came up.
そう｡
I see.
(ちんざむ)飲みにいくか｡
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)えっ？
Wanna get a drink?
Huh?
(ちんざむ)飲み足りねえなら➡
I'm saying that if you still wanna drink, I'll tag along.
付き合ってやってもいいって
言ってやってんだよ｡
(ﾎﾟﾆｰ)いいんですか？
(ちんざむ)えっ？
Are you sure?
You may have to listen to my complaints until morning.
朝まで ｸﾞﾁに 付き合って
もらうかもしれませんよ｡
ﾌｯ…｡
構やしねえさ｡
That's fine.
♪♪～
ｵﾚは もう
ｸﾞﾁの本当の意味を知ってるから｡
Since I understand the true meaning of a complaint.
(笑い声)
Wait!
(ｺﾞﾘ)待て！ ﾎﾟﾆｰちゃんと
手をつなぐなんて 許さん!!
I won't forgive you for holding hands with Pony-chan!
ｺﾞﾘさん ﾑﾘをするな！
背中に ﾈｷﾞが まだ刺さってるぞ！
Gori-san! Don't force yourself!
The green onion's still in your back!
(銀時)誰？ あれ｡
Who was that?
The next episode...
"Any place with a bunch of men gathered around will turn into a battlefield!"
[The Tsu Terakado Fanclub is in danger of disbanding! The cause of this crisis is...]
[(This week's complaint, or more like a realization) It's hard to do something you don't usually do.]
[See you next time.]